# Santiago Liñán R.

Systems engineer, software developer and entrepreneur. I have experience with software architectures, cloud computing, automated testing and mobile and web software development. I co-founded Polyglot, a software development startup in Colombia.

Bogotá, Colombia +57 300 697 81 86 s.linan10@uniandes.edu.co slinanromero@gmail.com https://github.com/slinan

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Universidad de los Andes, Colombia — Research assistant

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

My research areas are automated testing, mobile software development and automated code generation. I developed some of the contents for the programming introduction courses in Java. Currently I am part of "The Software Design Lab" research group.

#### **Polyglot**, Colombia — Co-founder and Software developer

IANUARY 2018 - PRESENT

I co-founded a custom software development startup. We have developed web and mobile applications related to healthcare, education and sales. I support DevOps tasks, cloud deployment, Linux server administration and software development in multiple languages (Python, Java, Javascript, Bash – Shell)

#### **Universidad de los Andes**, Colombia — Teaching assistant

FEBRUARY 2013 - MAY 2017

I have been teacher assistant during my undergraduate studies in different courses: Object-oriented programming, data structures and software development.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Universidad de los Andes,** Colombia — *MSc in Software Engineering*

JUNE 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

GPA: 4.65/5.0

### **Universidad de los Andes,** Colombia — B.S. in Systems and Computing engineering

JANUARY 2013 - DECEMBER 2016

GPA: 4.31/5.0

#### **SKILLS**

Proficient in Java, Python, Javascript and SQL. I have worked using frameworks like Django, Angular, Ionic and NodeJS.

DevOps and Linux administration

Cloud computing and distributed computing (Apache Spark)

Native and hybrid mobile software development

Agile/Scrum methodology

Software architectures

#### **AWARDS**

Winner at: "Bluehack Free Steps Against Human Trafficking" 2018.
Organized by the UN, UNODC and IBM.

NIER paper accepted at ICSME 2018 "Automated extraction of augmented models for Android apps"

Saber11 (ICFES) (National qualification exam after High School degree) 99th percentile score

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native English: Fluent Portuguese: Basic

#### **PROJECTS**

### Automated extraction of augmented models for Android apps — Research project

A proposed multi-model representation that combines information extracted statically and dynamically from an Android app. Our approach allows practitioners to automatically extract augmented models that combine different types of information such as context, domain and GUI, and could help them during comprehension and testing tasks. (Accepted at ICSME 2018)

### Find: A software platform against human trafficking — Software platform

Technological platform under development. This solution is being financed by the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime. It includes an AI module based on IBM Watson, mobile applications and a dashboard.

# ZILICIO: An Automation Framework for Rapid Native Mobile Application Development — Research project

An automation framework that allows developers to build real world apps in minutes for the two dominant mobile platforms (Android & iOS). Zilicio creates both Android and iOS versions of a mobile application, which is connected to an automatically generated RESTful backend, all through a friendly end-user web application.

### "El Club de los Tesos" App — Mobile app

A mobile app designed by the Engineering faculty of 'Universidad de los Andes' and developed by 'The Software Design Lab'. This initiative aims to increase bring closer college students to science and engineering.

### "Quiero Estudiar" App — Mobile app

A mobile app that help students with financial aid to follow their scholarship rules, find mentoring and track their progress in their soft skills.

# Hospital management system for an Emergency department in Colombia — WEB app

A web app that that shows in real time the occupancy of an emergency department. It also stores all the attention times and waiting times to guide the resource planning and evaluation of improvement policies.